Guide to the April Palmieri Papers 1980-1990 MSS 115
Fales Library and Special Collections
April Palmieri Papers
1980-1990
MSS 115
Fales Library and Special Collections
3.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
In the 1980's, April Palmieri was a member of the East Village band, Pulsallama, and a close friend of an eminent performer and member of the scene, John Sex. Included in the collection are Sex's videotapes of his performances, flyers, posters, and other materials about Palmieri and Sex.
Provenance
The April Palmieri Papers were the gift of April Palmieri in 2000.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival materials.
Historical/Biographical Note:
April Palmieri performed with a 12-piece all-girl percussion band, Pulsallama, that played at such venues as the Mudd Club, Danceteria, the Pyramid and Club 57 in New York's East Village during the early 1980's. She was also a close personal friend of eminent performer and member of the scene, John Sex. Following his death from AIDS in 1990, she received his collection of video tapes which contain his 1980's performances. These represent the most complete collection of video documenting Sex on stage. Also included in the collection are flyers, posters, and other materials about Palmieri and Sex. Other groups mentioned in the collection include the Bodacious Ta Ta's and the Fleshtones.
Scope and Content Note
The April Palmieri Papers are a part of the Downtown Collection at the Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU Libraries, housing nearly 200,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel, and the post-1975 Downtown New York scene.
The April Palmieri Papers consist of correspondence, flyers, newspaper clippings, and video recordings that are related to events and people associated with the New York City downtown scene of the 1980's.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
Series I contains the general files, which include correspondence, flyers, press releases, and newspaper clippings. These files are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Series II contains videos of performances and shows from the collection. These files are arranged chronologically and then alphabetically. [Research copies may not be available for these materials yet. Check with the Fales archivist.]
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically in Series I and chronologically within Series II.
The files are grouped into two series.
Series I: General Files
Series IIA: Videorecordings [Access Copies]
Series IIB: Videorecordings [Archival Originals]
Oversize
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Palmieri, April; Pulsallama (Musical Group).; Sex, John; Artists and community |z United States.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Fliers (printed matter); Male striptease.; New York (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.) |x Intellectual life |y 20th century.; Nightclubs.; Performance art |z United States.; Posters.; Videotapes.
- Series I: General Files
  - Club 57, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Club 57-Science Fair Show, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Danceteria/Wuthering Heights, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Flyers from Other Clubs/Venues, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Landis, Bill. Sleazoid Express, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Articles on the East Village, Music, and Fashion, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous: Photo of Tseng Kwong Chi, Unidentified Photocopies, M. Henry Jones Resume, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mudd Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Palmieri, April--Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pulsallama, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Read, John. Reunion on Avenue A (a play in one act), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sex, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Short, Jim. Short News, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Tina Peel, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series IIA: Videorecordings [Access Copies]
  - Pulsallama at Danceteria, 1/21/1983 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0002)
  - The John Sex Story, 11/1983-7/29/1985, 1983-1985 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0004)
  - Peter Pan at Danceteria, 12/22/1983 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0006)
  - Pyramid NHK Show-Richard Metzger, Transfer, 1985 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0008)
  - Cutting Edge, June 1985; Fleshtones, Space Party, John Sex and Bodacious TaTas at the Limelight, 6/15/1985 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0010)
  - CNN News Interview, 7/2/1986 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0012)
  - Pyramid Show, 10/17/1986 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0014)
  - Club Nu Show, 4/24/1987 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0016)
  - Sex, John in Graceland, Vancouver, 4/11/1988 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0018)
  - Baci Italiani, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0021)
  - Baci Italiani at Limelight, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0023)
  - Micki, John/CNN/Danceteria/Liberace Radio City, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0025)
  - Rubnitz, Tom. "Undercover Me!", undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0027)
  - The Saint-Birthday Show; Bye Bye Birdie, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0029)
  - Sex, John-Bump and Grind, Pulsallama, Hustle with My Muscle, Crime of the Heart, Angelynne, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0031)
  - Sex, John-Extra Exit Fashion Show, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0033)
  - Sex, John-Palladium Show, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0035)
  - Pulsallama at Danceteria, 1/21/1983 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0038)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Format: DVD
    TRT: 00:33:00
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic
    Source: ID: 115.0001
  - The John Sex Story, 11/1983- 7/29/1985 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0040)
    TRT: 02:01:00
    Original Format: VHS
    Source ID: 115.0003
  - Peter Pan at Danceteria, 12/22/1983 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0042)
    TRT: 01:57:00
    Source ID: 115.0005
  - Pyramid NHK Show, 1985 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0044)
    TRT: 00:18:00
    Source ID: 115.0007
  - Cutting Edge; Fleshtones, Space Party, John Sex and Bodacious TaTas at the Limelight, 6/15/1985 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0046)
    TRT: 01:16:30
    Source ID: 115.0009
  - CNN News Interview WITH John Sex, 7/2/1986 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0048)
    TRT: 00:07:00
    Source ID: 115.0011
  - Pyramid Show, 10/17/1986 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0050)
    TRT: 00:56:30
    Source ID: 115.0013
  - Club Nu Show, 4/24/1987 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0052)
    TRT: 00:25:00
    Source ID: 115.0015
  - John Sex in Graceland, Vancouver, 4/11/1988 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0054)
    TRT: 00:58:45
    Source ID: 115.0017
  - Baci Italiani (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0056)
    TRT: 00:55:00
    Source ID: 115.0020
  - Baci Italiani at Limelight (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0058)
    TRT: 01:12:00
    Source ID: 115.0022
  - CNN (Danceteria Footage)/ ABC NEWS: Liberace Radio City/ John Sex montage (silent) (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0060)
    TRT: 00:30:00
    Source ID: 115.0025
  - Rubnitz, Tom. "Undercover Me!" (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0062)
    TRT: 00:04:00
    Source ID: 115.0026
  - The Saint- Birthday Show; Bye Bye Birdie (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0064)
    TRT: 00:54:00
    Source ID: 115.0028
  - John Sex-Bump and Grind, Pulsallama,… (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0066)
    TRT: 00:38:00
    Source ID: 115.0030
  - Extra Exit Fashion Show & John Sex (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0068)
    TRT: 01:29:00
    Source ID: 115.0032
  - John Sex; Live at 5; Palladium Show (Shelf Media, Media ID: 115.0070)
    Source ID: 115.0034
- Series IIB: Videorecordings [Archival Originals]
  - Pulsallama at Danceteria, 1/21/1983 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0001)
  - The John Sex Story, 11/1983-7/29/1985, 1983-1985 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0003)
  - Peter Pan at Danceteria, 12/22/1983 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0005)
  - Pyramid NHK Show-Richard Metzger, Transfer, 1985 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0007)
  - Cutting Edge, June 1985; Fleshtones, Space Party, John Sex and Bodacious TaTas at the Limelight, 6/15/1985 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0009)
  - CNN News Interview, 7/2/1986 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0011)
  - Pyramid Show, 10/17/1986 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0013)
  - Club Nu Show, 4/24/1987 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0015)
  - Sex, John in Graceland, Vancouver, 4/11/1988 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0017)
  - Sex, John. "Rock Your Body" Dream Records (Reel) 9/14/1988 (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0019)
  - Baci Italiani, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0020)
  - Baci Italiani at Limelight, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0022)
  - Micki, John/CNN/Danceteria/Liberace Radio City, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0024)
  - Rubnitz, Tom. "Undercover Me!", undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0026)
  - The Saint-Birthday Show; Bye Bye Birdie, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0028)
  - Sex, John-Bump and Grind, Pulsallama, Hustle with My Muscle, Crime of the Heart, Angelynne, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0030)
  - Sex, John-Extra Exit Fashion Show, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0032)
  - Sex, John-Palladium Show, undated (Box media shelves, Folder ID: 115.0034)
- Oversize
  - Flyers and Newspaper Clippings re: John Sex, Club 57, Mudd Club, etc., undated (Box 3)